<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preclasses on PHP 1560/2560: Statistical Programming with R</title>
    <link>/preclass/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preclasses on PHP 1560/2560: Statistical Programming with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/preclass/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 01 Preclass</title>
      <link>/preclass/01-preclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preclass/01-preclass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to PHP 1560&amp;frasl;2560. This course is all about how to become a proficient programmer in R. In order to become an R Programmer you must actually practice coding and working in R.
This course is what we call a flipped course. A flipped course is where we have the lecture at home and then in the classroom we focus on hands on learning.
Each week before class you will have a series of Pre-Class work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 02 Preclass</title>
      <link>/preclass/02-preclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preclass/02-preclass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We have started to use RStudio and Github. Now is your time to get more acquainted with R itself. We will start working with some of the very basic tools of R.
Flipped Material  Sign into Datacamp Complete Chapter 1 Complete Manipulate Data in R Complete the pre-class work.  This link will create a github repository. Clone this on your computer, change the readme as directed, commit, then proceed to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 03 Preclass</title>
      <link>/preclass/03-preclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preclass/03-preclass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We have started to use RStudio and Github. Now is your time to get more acquainted with R itself. We will start working with some of the very basic tools of R.
Flipped Material  Sign into Datacamp Complete Joining Data in R with dplyr course. Complete these steps for the assignment:  Create a new folder in your pre-class Repository called: Week 03 Copy the readme.md and pre-class-03.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 04 Preclass</title>
      <link>/preclass/04-preclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preclass/04-preclass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We wil begin to learn how to use R to a much higher level.
Flipped Material  Sign into Datacamp Complete Chapters 3: Flow Control and Initial Functions from PHP 1560&amp;frasl;2560 Statistical Programing with R. Complete Intermediate R Course. Complete these steps for the assignment:  Create a new folder in your pre-class Repository called: Week 04 Copy the readme.md and pre-class-04.Rmd document into this. Follow the instructions and commit often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 05 Preclass</title>
      <link>/preclass/05-preclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preclass/05-preclass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We will begin working with functions in R.
Flipped Material  Sign into Datacamp Complete Chapters 4: Functions from PHP 1560&amp;frasl;2560 Statistical Programing with R. Complete Writing Functions in R Course Complete these steps for the assignment:  Create a new folder in your pre-class Repository called: Week 05 Copy the readme.md and pre-class-05.Rmd document into this. Follow the instructions and commit often.    In-Class Problems  Find the files here Save the README.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 06 Preclass</title>
      <link>/preclass/06-preclass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/preclass/06-preclass/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This Class will be working with Functions again. This means there is little new material however, there is some good reading you should all do.
Required Reading  R For Data Science: Functions Chapter Functional Programming - Advanced R Functionals Function Operators   In-Class Problems  Find the files here Save the README.md and pre-class-05.Rmd in your pre-class repository under a new folder called Week 06. Remember to commit often.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>